<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37365541</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-244X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prediction of early improvement of major depressive disorder to antidepressant medication in adolescents with radiomics analysis after ComBat harmonization based on multiscale structural MRI.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>466</StartPage><MedlinePgn>466</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12888-023-04966-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Due to individual differences and lack of objective biomarkers, only 30-40% patients with major depressive disorder (MDD) achieve remission after initial antidepressant medication (ADM). We aimed to employ radiomics analysis after ComBat harmonization to predict early improvement to ADM in adolescents with MDD by using brain multiscale structural MRI (sMRI) and identify the radiomics features with high prediction power for selection of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and serotonin norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">121 MDD patients were recruited for brain sMRI, including three-dimensional T1 weighted imaging (3D-T<sub>1</sub>WI)and diffusion tensor imaging (DTI). After receiving SSRIs or SNRIs for 2 weeks, the subjects were divided into ADM improvers (SSRIs improvers and SNRIs improvers) and non-improvers according to reduction rate of the Hamilton Depression Rating Scale, 17 item (HAM-D<sub>17</sub>) score. Then, sMRI data were preprocessed, and conventional imaging indicators and radiomics features of gray matter (GM) based on surface-based morphology (SBM) and voxel-based morphology (VBM) and diffusion properties of white matter (WM) were extracted and harmonized with ComBat harmonization. Two-level reduction strategy with analysis of variance (ANOVA) and recursive feature elimination (RFE) was utilized sequentially to decrease high-dimensional features. Support vector machine with radial basis function kernel (RBF-SVM) was used to integrate multiscale sMRI features to construct models for early improvement prediction. Area under the curve (AUC), accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity based on the leave-one-out cross-validation (LOO-CV) and receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis were calculated to evaluate the model performance. Permutation tests were used for assessing the generalization rate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After 2-week ADM, 121 patients were divided into 67 ADM improvers (31 SSRIs improvers and 36 SNRIs improvers) and 54 ADM non-improvers. After two-level dimensionality reduction, 8 conventional indicators (2 VBM-based features and 6 diffusion features) and 49 radiomics features (16 VBM-based features and 33 diffusion features) were selected. The overall accuracy of RBF-SVM models based on conventional indicators and radiomics features was 74.80% and 88.19%. The radiomics model achieved the AUC, sensitivity, specificity, and accuracy of 0.889, 91.2%, 80.1% and 85.1%, 0.954, 89.2%, 87.4% and 88.5%, 0.942, 91.9%, 82.5% and 86.8% for predicting ADM improvers, SSRIs improvers and SNRIs improvers, respectively. P value of permutation tests were less than 0.001. The radiomics features predicting ADM improver were mainly located in the hippocampus, medial orbitofrontal gyrus, anterior cingulate gyrus, cerebellum (lobule vii-b), body of corpus callosum, etc. The radiomics features predicting SSRIs improver were primarily distributed in hippocampus, amygdala, inferior temporal gyrus, thalamus, cerebellum (lobule vi), fornix, cerebellar peduncle, etc. The radiomics features predicting SNRIs improver were primarily located in the medial orbitofrontal cortex, anterior cingulate gyrus, ventral striatum, corpus callosum, etc. CONCLUSIONS: These findings suggest the radiomics analysis based on brain multiscale sMRI after ComBat harmonization could effectively predict the early improvement of ADM in adolescent MDD patients with a high accuracy, which was superior to the model based on the conventional indicators. The radiomics features with high prediction power may help for the individual selection of SSRIs and SNRIs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Huan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, 650018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, 650101, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Dafu</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, 650018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, 650018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Yingying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, 650018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Jianzhong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, 650101, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Kun</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, 650018, China. 353142503@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968559</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-244X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antidepressant medication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Major depressive disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radiomics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37365541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-023-04966-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12888-023-04966-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hasin DS, Sarvet AL, Meyers JL, et al. Epidemiology of adult DSM-5 major depressive disorder and its specifiers in the United States. JAMA Psychiatry. 2018;75(4):336&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29450462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5875313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.4602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice F, Riglin L, Lomax T, Souter E, Potter R, Smith DJ, Thapar AK, Thapar A. Adolescent and adult differences in major depression symptom profiles. J Affect Disord. 2019;243:175&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30243197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2018.09.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeMoult J, Humphreys KL, Tracy A, Hoffmeister JA, Ip E, Gotlib IH. Meta-analysis: exposure to early life stress and risk for depression in childhood and adolescence. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2020;59(7):842&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31676392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2019.10.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter HJ, Abright AR, Bukstein OG, Diamond J, Keable H, Ripperger-Suhler J, Rockhill C. Clinical practice guideline for the assessment and treatment of children and adolescents with major and persistent depressive disorders. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2022;21:S0890-8567(22)01852-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Xiao L, Wang WW, Ungvari GS, Ng CH, Wang G, Xiang YT. Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of depressive disorders in China: the second edition. J Affect Disord. 2019;253:352&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2019.04.104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avenevoli S, Swendsen J, He JP, Burstein M, Merikangas KR. Major depression in the national comorbidity survey-adolescent supplement: prevalence, correlates, and treatment. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2015;54(1):37&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25524788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2014.10.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Barrett MS, Cucchiara AJ, Gooneratne NS, Thase ME. A breathing-based meditation intervention for patients with major depressive disorder following inadequate response to antidepressants: a randomized pilot study. J Clin Psychiatry. 2017;78(1):59&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.16m10819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadi&#x107; A, Wachtlin D, Berger M, Braus DF, van Calker D, Dahmen N, Dreim&#xfc;ller N, Engel A, Gorbulev S, Helmreich I, Kaiser AK, Kronfeld K, Schlicht KF, T&#xfc;scher O, Wagner S, Hiemke C, Lieb K. Randomized controlled study of early medication change for non-improvers to antidepressant therapy in major depression-the EMC trial. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2016;26(4):705&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26899588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2016.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel V, Seem&#xfc;ller F, Obermeier M, Adli M, Bauer M, Mundt C, Brieger P, Laux G, Bender W, Heuser I, Zeiler J, Gaebel W, Mayr A, M&#xf6;ller HJ, Riedel M. Does early improvement triggered by antidepressants predict response/remission? Analysis of data from a naturalistic study on a large sample of inpatients with major depression. J Affect Disord. 2009;115(3):439&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19027961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2008.10.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szegedi A, Jansen WT, van Willigenburg AP, Stassen HH, Thase ME. Early improvement in the first 2 weeks as a predictor of treatment outcome in patients with major depressive disorder: a meta-analysis including 6562 patients. J Clin Psychiatry. 2009;70(3):344&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19254516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.07m03780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JM, Kim SY, Stewart R, Yoo JA, Bae KY, Jung SW, Lee MS, Yim HW, Jun TY. Improvement within 2 weeks and later treatment outcomes in patients with depressive disorders: the CRESCEND study. J Affect Disord. 2011;129(1&#x2013;3):183&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20875918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2010.09.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maller JJ, Broadhouse K, Rush AJ, Gordon E, Koslow S, Grieve SM. Increased hippocampal tail volume predicts depression status and remission to anti-depressant medications in major depression. Mol Psychiatry. 2018;23(8):1737&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29133948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2017.224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saricicek Aydogan A, Oztekin E, Esen ME, Dusmez S, Gelal F, Besiro&#x11f;lu L, Zorlu N. Cortical thickening in remitters compared to non-remitters with major depressive disorder following 8-week antidepressant treatment. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2019;140(3):217&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31250445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.13065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartlett EA, DeLorenzo C, Sharma P, Yang J, Zhang M, Petkova E, Weissman M, McGrath PJ, Fava M, Ogden RT, Kurian BT, Malchow A, Cooper CM, Trombello JM, McInnis M, Adams P, Oquendo MA, Pizzagalli DA, Trivedi M, Parsey RV. Pretreatment and early-treatment cortical thickness is associated with SSRI treatment response in major depressive disorder. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2018;43(11):2221&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29955151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6135779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-018-0122-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve SM, Korgaonkar MS, Gordon E, Williams LM, Rush AJ. Prediction of nonremission to antidepressant therapy using diffusion tensor imaging. J Clin Psychiatry. 2016;77(4):e436&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27137427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.14m09577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoogenboom WS, Perlis RH, Smoller JW, et al. Limbic system white matter microstructure and long-term treatment outcome in major depressive disorder: a diffusion tensor imaging study using legacy data. World J Biol Psychiatry. 2014;15(2):122&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22540406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/15622975.2012.669499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CH. Fronto-limbic neuroimaging biomarkers for diagnosis and prediction of treatment responses in major depressive disorder. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2021;107:110234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33370569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2020.110234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning L, Rathi Y, Barbour T, Makris N, Camprodon JA. White matter markers and predictors for subject-specific rTMS response in major depressive disorder. J Affect Disord. 2022;299:207&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34875281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2021.12.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue L, Pei C, Wang X, Wang H, Tian S, Yao Z, Lu Q. Predicting neuroimaging biomarkers for antidepressant selection in early treatment of depression. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;54(2):551&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33634921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.27577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis AD, Hassel S, Arnott SR, Harris J, Lam RW, Milev R, Rotzinger S, Zamyadi M, Frey BN, Minuzzi L, Strother SC, MacQueen GM, Kennedy SH, Hall GB. White matter indices of medication response in major depression: a diffusion tensor imaging study. Biol Psychiatry Cogn Neurosci Neuroimaging. 2019;4(10):913&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31471185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin Fatt CR, Jha MK, Cooper CM, Fonzo G, South C, Grannemann B, Carmody T, Greer TL, Kurian B, Fava M, McGrath PJ, Adams P, McInnis M, Parsey RV, Weissman M, Phillips ML, Etkin A, Trivedi MH. Effect of intrinsic patterns of functional brain connectivity in moderating antidepressant treatment response in major depression. Am J Psychiatry. 2020;177(2):143&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2019.18070870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Lu C, Gao Z, et al. SNRIs achieve faster antidepressant effects than SSRIs by elevating the concentrations of dopamine in the forebrain. Neuropharmacology. 2020;177:108237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32710978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2020.108237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy SH, Konarski JZ, Segal ZV, Lau MA, Bieling PJ, McIntyre RS, Mayberg HS. Differences in brain glucose metabolism between responders to CBT and venlafaxine in a 16-week randomized controlled trial. Am J Psychiatry. 2007;164(5):778&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17475737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.2007.164.5.778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wattiez AS, Dupuis A, Privat AM, Chalus M, Chapuy E, Aissouni Y, Eschalier A, Courteix C. Disruption of 5-HT2A-PDZ protein interaction differently affects the analgesic efficacy of SSRI, SNRI and TCA in the treatment of traumatic neuropathic pain in rats. Neuropharmacology. 2017;125:308&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28780039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2017.07.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillies RJ, Kinahan PE, Hricak H. Radiomics: images are more than pictures, they are data. Radiology. 2016;278(2):563&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26579733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2015151169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rondina JM, Ferreira LK, de Souza Duran FL, Kubo R, Ono CR, Leite CC, Smid J, Nitrini R, Buchpiguel CA, Busatto GF. Selecting the most relevant brain regions to discriminate Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease patients from healthy controls using multiple kernel learning: a comparison across functional and structural imaging modalities and atlases. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;17:628&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29234599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5716956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.10.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang K, Lin Y, Yang L, Wang Y, Cai S, Pang L, Wu X, Huang L. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative. A multipredictor model to predict the conversion of mild cognitive impairment to Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease by using a predictive nomogram. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2020;45(2):358&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31634898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-019-0551-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Sun K, Liu Z, Chen G, Jia Y, Zhong S, Pan J, Huang L, Tian J. Classification of unmedicated bipolar disorder using whole-brain functional activity and connectivity: a radiomics analysis. Cereb Cortex. 2020;30(3):1117&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31408101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhz152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Chen Y, Huang Q, Lui S, Huang X, Shi Y, Xu X, Sweeney JA, Gong Q. Psychoradiologic utility of MR imaging for diagnosis of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: a radiomics analysis. Radiology. 2018;287(2):620&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29165048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2017170226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlhac F, Lecler A, Savatovski J, Goya-Outi J, Nioche C, Charbonneau F, Ayache N, Frouin F, Duron L, Buvat I. How can we combat multicenter variability in MR radiomics? Validation of a correction procedure. Eur Radiol. 2021;31(4):2272&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32975661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-020-07284-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leithner D, Sch&#xf6;der H, Haug A, Vargas HA, Gibbs P, H&#xe4;ggstr&#xf6;m I, Rausch I, Weber M, Becker AS, Schwartz J, Mayerhoefer ME. Impact of ComBat harmonization on PET radiomics-based tissue classification: a dual-center PET/MRI and PET/CT study. J Nucl Med. 2022;63(10):1611&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35210300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9536705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.121.263102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saint Martin MJ, Orlhac F, Akl P, Khalid F, Nioche C, Buvat I, Malhaire C, Frouin F. A radiomics pipeline dedicated to breast MRI: validation on a multi-scanner phantom study. MAGMA. 2021;34(3):355&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33180226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10334-020-00892-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortin JP, Parker D, Tun&#xe7; B, Watanabe T, Elliott MA, Ruparel K, Roalf DR, Satterthwaite TD, Gur RC, Gur RE, Schultz RT, Verma R, Shinohara RT. Harmonization of multi-site diffusion tensor imaging data. NeuroImage. 2017;161:149&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28826946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.08.047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H, Zhang D, Sun D, Wang H, Yang J. Gray and white matter structural examination for diagnosis of major depressive disorder and subthreshold depression in adolescents and young adults: a preliminary radiomics analysis. BMC Med Imaging. 2022;22(1):164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36096776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9465920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12880-022-00892-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin HS, Lin CH. Early improvement in HAMD-17 and HAMD-6 scores predicts ultimate response and remission for depressed patients treated with fluoxetine or ECT. J Affect Disord. 2019;245:91&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30368075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2018.10.105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander B, Loh WY, Matthews LG, Murray AL, Adamson C, Beare R, Chen J, Kelly CE, Anderson PJ, Doyle LW, Spittle AJ, Cheong JLY, Seal ML, Thompson DK. Desikan-Killiany-Tourville atlas compatible version of M-CRIB neonatal parcellated whole brain atlas: the M-CRIB 2.0. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30804737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6371012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2019.00034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tustison NJ, Cook PA, Klein A, Song G, Das SR, Duda JT, Kandel BM, van Strien N, Stone JR, Gee JC, Avants BB. Large-scale evaluation of ANTs and FreeSurfer cortical thickness measurements. NeuroImage. 2014;99:166&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24879923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2014.05.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh A, Kaur S, Shah R, Oomer F, Avasthi A, Ahuja CK, Basu D, Nehra R, Khandelwal N. Surface-based brain morphometry in schizophrenia vs. cannabis-induced psychosis: a controlled comparison. J Psychiatr Res. 2022;155:286&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36170756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2022.09.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dovrou A, Nikiforaki K, Zaridis D, Manikis GC, Mylona E, Tachos N, Tsiknakis M, Fotiadis DI, Marias K. A segmentation-based method improving the performance of N4 bias field correction on T2weighted MR imaging data of the prostate. Magn Reson Imaging. 2023;101:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37004467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mri.2023.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettinelli A, Marturano F, Avanzo M, Loi E, Menghi E, Mezzenga E, Pirrone G, Sarnelli A, Strigari L, Strolin S, Paiusco M. A novel benchmarking approach to assess the agreement among radiomic tools. Radiology. 2022;303(3):533&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35230182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.211604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadarella G, Stanzione A, Akinci D&#x2019;Antonoli T, Andreychenko A, Fanni SC, Ugga L, Kotter E, Cuocolo R. Systematic review of the radiomics quality score applications: an EuSoMII radiomics auditing group initiative. Eur Radiol. 2023;33(3):1884&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36282312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-022-09187-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Ghosh K, Sakaie K, Sahoo SS, Carr SJA, Tatsuoka C. A simplified crossing fiber model in diffusion weighted imaging. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6541109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2019.00492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Qin Y, Chen H, Cheng J, He B, Wan Y, Zhu D, Gao F, Zhou X. Machine learning to differentiate small round cell malignant tumors and non-small round cell malignant tumors of the nasal and paranasal sinuses using apparent diffusion coefficient values. Eur Radiol. 2022;32(6):3819&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35029732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9123077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-021-08465-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan EB, Banaschewski T, Barker GJ, Bokde ALW, Bromberg U, B&#xfc;chel C, Desrivi&#xe8;res S, Flor H, Frouin V, Garavan H, Heinz A, Br&#xfc;hl R, Martinot JL, Paill&#xe8;re Martinot ML, Nees F, Orfanos DP, Paus T, Poustka L, Hohmann S, Smolka MN, Fr&#xf6;hner JH, Walter H, Whelan R, Schumann G, IMAGEN Consortium. Identifying biological markers for improved precision medicine in psychiatry. Mol Psychiatry. 2020;25(2):243&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31676814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-019-0555-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein-Piekarski AN, Holt-Gosselin B, O&#x2019;Hora K, Williams LM. Integrating sleep, neuroimaging, and computational approaches for precision psychiatry. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2020;45(1):192&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31426055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-019-0483-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salzman CD, Fusi S. Emotion, cognition, and mental state representation in amygdala and prefrontal cortex. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2010;33:173&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20331363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3108339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.neuro.051508.135256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McRae K, Gross JJ. Emotion regulation. Emotion. 2020;20(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31961170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/emo0000703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vald&#xe9;s-Tovar M, Estrada-Reyes R, Sol&#xed;s-Chagoy&#xe1;n H, Argueta J, Dorantes-Barr&#xf3;n AM, Quero-Ch&#xe1;vez D, Cruz-Gardu&#xf1;o R, Cerc&#xf3;s MG, Trueta C, Oikawa-Sala J, Dubocovich ML, Ben&#xed;tez-King G. Circadian modulation of neuroplasticity by melatonin: a target in the treatment of depression. Br J Pharmacol. 2018;175(16):3200&#x2013;08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6057892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.14197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serafini G. Neuroplasticity and major depression, the role of modern antidepressant drugs. World J Psychiatry. 2012;2(3):49&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24175168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3782176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v2.i3.49</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson TC, Obiang P, Torres-Herraez A, Watilliaux A, Coulon P, Rochefort C, Rondi-Reig L. Anatomical and physiological foundations of cerebello-hippocampal interaction. Elife. 2019;8:e41896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31205000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6579515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.41896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jannini TB, Lorenzo GD, Bianciardi E, Niolu C, Toscano M, Ciocca G, Jannini EA, Siracusano A. Off-label uses of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs). Curr Neuropharmacol. 2022;20(4):693&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33998993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9878961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159X19666210517150418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leshem R, Bar-Oz B, Diav-Citrin O, Gbaly S, Soliman J, Renoux C, Matok I. Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and serotonin norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs) during pregnancy and the risk for autism spectrum disorder (ASD) and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) in the offspring: a true effect or a bias? A systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2021;19(6):896&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8686301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159X19666210303121059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Zhao YJ, Hu XY, Du MY, Chen ZQ, Wu M, Li KM, Zhu HY, Kumar P, Gong QY. Microstructural brain abnormalities in medication-free patients with major depressive disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis of diffusion tensor imaging. J Psychiatry Neurosci. 2017;42(3):150&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27780031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/jpn.150341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SJ, Cheng J, Jang JH, Arace J, Jeong M, Shin CH, Park J, Jin J, Greengard P, Oh YS. Hippocampal mossy cell involvement in behavioral and neurogenic responses to chronic antidepressant treatment. Mol Psychiatry. 2020;25(6):1215&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-019-0384-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekhbat M, Li Z, Mehta ND, Treadway MT, Lucido MJ, Woolwine BJ, Haroon E, Miller AH, Felger JC. Functional connectivity in reward circuitry and symptoms of anhedonia as therapeutic targets in depression with high inflammation: evidence from a dopamine challenge study. Mol Psychiatry. 2022;27(10):4113&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35927580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9718669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-022-01715-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang FF, Peng W, Sweeney JA, Jia ZY, Gong QY. Brain structure alterations in depression: psychoradiological evidence. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2018;24(11):994&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29508560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6489983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cns.12835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Leri F, Rizvi SJ. Anhedonia as a central factor in depression: neural mechanisms revealed from preclinical to clinical evidence. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2021;110:110289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2021.110289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37365362</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1614-7499</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental science and pollution research international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Simultaneous identification of groundwater pollution source and important hydrogeological parameters considering the noise uncertainty of observational data.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11356-023-28091-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Groundwater pollution identification is an inverse problem. When solving the inverse problem using regular methods such as simulation-optimization or stochastic statistical approaches, requires repeatedly calling the simulation model for forward calculations, which is a time-consuming process. Currently, the problem is often solved by building a surrogate model for the simulation model. However, the surrogate model is only an intermediate step in regular methods, such as the simulation-optimization method that also require the creation and solution of an optimization model with the minimum objective function, which adds complexity and time to the inversion task and presents an obstacle to achieving fast inversion. In the present study, the extreme gradient boosting (XGBoost) method and the back propagation neural network (BPNN) method were used to directly establish the mapping relationships between the output and input of the simulation model, which could directly obtain the inversion results of the variables to be identified (pollution sources release histories and hydraulic conductivities) based on actual observational data for fast inversion. In addition, to consider the uncertainty of observation data noise, the inversion accuracy of the two machine learning methods was compared, and the method with higher precision was selected for the uncertainty analysis. The results indicated that both the BPNN and XGBoost methods could perform inversion tasks well, with a mean absolute percentage error (MAPE) of 4.15% and 1.39%, respectively. Using the BPNN, with better accuracy for uncertainty analysis, when the maximum probabilistic density value was selected as the inversion result, the MAPE was 2.13%. We obtained the inversion results under different confidence levels and decision makers of groundwater pollution prevention and control can choose different inversion results according to their needs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Chengming</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Groundwater Resources and Environment, Ministry of Education, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jilin Provincial Key Laboratory of Water Resources and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of New Energy and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Wenxi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Groundwater Resources and Environment, Ministry of Education, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China. luwx999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jilin Provincial Key Laboratory of Water Resources and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China. luwx999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of New Energy and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China. luwx999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Zidong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Groundwater Resources and Environment, Ministry of Education, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jilin Provincial Key Laboratory of Water Resources and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of New Energy and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Yukun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Groundwater Resources and Environment, Ministry of Education, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jilin Provincial Key Laboratory of Water Resources and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of New Energy and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Guangqi</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Groundwater Resources and Environment, Ministry of Education, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jilin Provincial Key Laboratory of Water Resources and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of New Energy and Environment, Jilin University, Changchun, 130021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9441769</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0944-1344</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Back propagation neural network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Extreme gradient boosting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Groundwater pollution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simultaneous identification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Uncertainty analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37365362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-023-28091-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11356-023-28091-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>An Y, Yan X, Lu W, Qian H, Zhang Z (2022) An improved Bayesian approach linked to a surrogate model for identifying groundwater pollution sources. Hydrogeol J 30(2):601&#x2013;616. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10040-021-02411-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10040-021-02411-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anshuman A, Eldho TI (2022) Entity aware sequence to sequence learning using LSTMs for estimation of groundwater contamination release history and transport parameters. J Hydrol 608. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2022.127662</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asher MJ, Croke BFW, Jakeman AJ, Peeters LJM (2015) A review of surrogate models and their application to groundwater modeling. Water Resour Res 51(8):5957&#x2013;5973. https://doi.org/10.1002/2015wr016967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2015wr016967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayvaz MT (2010) A linked simulation-optimization model for solving the unknown groundwater pollution source identification problems. J Contam Hydrol 117(1-4):46&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jconhyd.2010.06.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconhyd.2010.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y, Lu W, Li J, Chang Z, Wang H (2022) Groundwater contamination source identification using improved differential evolution Markov chain algorithm. Environ Sci Pollut Res 29(13):19679&#x2013;19692. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-021-17120-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-021-17120-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Z., Lu, W., Wang, Z., 2021. A differential evolutionary Markov chain algorithm with ensemble smoother initial point selection for the identification of groundwater contaminant sources. J Hydrol 603. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2021.126918</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De'ath G, Fabricius KE (2000) Classification and regression trees: A powerful yet simple technique for ecological data analysis. Ecology 81(11):3178&#x2013;3192. https://doi.org/10.1890/0012-9658(2000)081[3178:Cartap]2.0.Co;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/0012-9658(2000)081[3178:Cartap]2.0.Co;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dieu Tien B et al (2016) Hybrid artificial intelligence approach based on neural fuzzy inference model and metaheuristic optimization for flood susceptibilitgy modeling in a high-frequency tropical cyclone area using GIS. J Hydrol 540:317&#x2013;330. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2016.06.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2016.06.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorigo M, Birattari M, Stuetzle T (2006) Ant colony optimization - Artificial ants as a computational intelligence technique. IEEE Comput Intell Mag 1(4):28&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.1109/mci.2006.329691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/mci.2006.329691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorigo M, Di Caro G, Gambardella LM (1999) Ant algorithms for discrete optimization. Art&amp;Life 5(2):137&#x2013;172. https://doi.org/10.1162/106454699568728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/106454699568728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y et al (2020) Optimal design of groundwater pollution monitoring network based on the SVR surrogate model under uncertainty. Environ Sci Pollut Res 27(19):24090&#x2013;24102. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-020-08758-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-08758-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H, Wang J, Ao W, He Y (2018) SGB-ELM: An Advanced Stochastic Gradient Boosting-Based Ensemble Scheme for Extreme Learning Machine. Comput Intell Neurosci 2018. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/4058403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Q, Dai F, Zhao Z (2020) Comparison of Two Bayesian-MCMC Inversion Methods for Laboratory Infiltration and Field Irrigation Experiments. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17(3). https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17031108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z, Moosavi V, Leitao JPP (2022) Data-driven rapid flood prediction mapping with catchment generalizability. J Hydrol 609. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2022.127726</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Z et al (2021) Optimal location of cutoff walls for seawater intrusion. Applied Water. Science 11(11). https://doi.org/10.1007/s13201-021-01514-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Z, Lu W (2018) Comparative study of surrogate models for groundwater contamination source identification at DNAPL-contaminated sites. Hydrogeol J 26(3):923&#x2013;932. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10040-017-1690-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10040-017-1690-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang S et al. (2021) Simultaneous identification of contaminant sources and hydraulic conductivity field by combining geostatistics method with self-organizing maps algorithm. J Contam Hydrol 241. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jconhyd.2021.103815</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkpatrick S, Gelatt CD, Vecchi MP (1983) Optimization by Simulated Annealing. Science 220(4598):671&#x2013;680. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.220.4598.671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.220.4598.671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo YM, Liu CW, Lin KH (2004) Evaluation of the ability of an artificial neural network model to assess the variation of groundwater quality in an area of blackfoot disease in Taiwan. Water Res 38(1):148&#x2013;158. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2003.09.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2003.09.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Lu W, Wang H, Fan Y, Chang Z (2020) Groundwater contamination source identification based on a hybrid particle swarm optimization-extreme learning machine. J Hydrol 584. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2020.124657</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Wu Z, He H, Lu W (2022) Identification of light nonaqueous phase liquid groundwater contamination source based on empirical mode decomposition and deep learning. Environ Sci Pollut Res. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-022-24671-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y-P, Chu H-J, Huang Y-L, Cheng B-Y, Chang T-K (2011) Modeling spatial uncertainty of heavy metal content in soil by conditional Latin hypercube sampling and geostatistical simulation. Environ Earth Sci 62(2):299&#x2013;311. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12665-010-0523-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-010-0523-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahinthakumar GK, Sayeed M (2006) Reconstructing groundwater source release histories using hybrid optimization approaches. Environ Forensic 7(1):45&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1080/15275920500506774</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15275920500506774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghaddam MB, Mazaheri M, Samani JMV (2021) Inverse modeling of contaminant transport for pollution source identification in surface and groundwaters: a review. Groundw Sustain Dev 15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gsd.2021.100651</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Z, Lu W, Bai Y (2022) Groundwater contamination source estimation based on a refined particle filter associated with a deep residual neural network surrogate. Hydrogeol J 30(3):881&#x2013;897. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10040-022-02454-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10040-022-02454-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Z, Lu W, Chang Z, Wang H (2021) Simultaneous identification of groundwater pollution source spatial-temporal characteristics and hydraulic parameters based on deep regularization neural network-hybrid heuristic algorithm. J Hydrol 600. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2021.126586</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei W et al (2016) Using Monte Carlo simulation to assess uncertainty and variability of methamphetamine use and prevalence from wastewater analysis. Int J Drug Policy 36:1&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugpo.2016.06.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugpo.2016.06.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razavi S, Tolson BA, Burn DH (2012) Review of surrogate modeling in water resources. Water Resour Res 48. https://doi.org/10.1029/2011wr011527</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savic DA, Walters GA (1997) Genetic algorithms for least-cost design of water distribution networks. J Water Resour Plann Manage-Asce 123(2):67&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1061/(asce)0733-9496(1997)123:2(67)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)0733-9496(1997)123:2(67)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secci D, Molino L, Zanini A (2022) Contaminant source identification in groundwater by means of artificial neural network. J Hydrol 611. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2022.128003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen S et al (2014) Markov Chain Monte Carlo Approach for Parameter Uncertainty Quantification and Its Impact on Groundwater Mass Transport Modeling: Influence of Prior Distribution. Environ Eng Sci 31(9):487&#x2013;495. https://doi.org/10.1089/ees.2012.0236</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ees.2012.0236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shieh HJ, Peralta RC (2005) Optimal in situ bioremediation design by hybrid genetic algorithm-simulated annealing. J Water Resour Plann Manage-Asce 131(1):67&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1061/(asce)0733-9496(2005)131:1(67)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)0733-9496(2005)131:1(67)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields MD, Zhang J (2016) The generalization of Latin hypercube sampling. Reliab Eng Syst Saf 148:96&#x2013;108. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ress.2015.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ress.2015.12.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P, Singh RM (2019) Identification of pollution sources using artificial neural network (ANN) and multilevel breakthrough curve (BTC) characterization. Environ Forensic 20(3):219&#x2013;227. https://doi.org/10.1080/15275922.2019.1629548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15275922.2019.1629548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh RM, Datta B (2004) Groundwater pollution source identification and simultaneous parameter estimation using pattern matching by artificial neural network. Environ Forensic 5(3):143&#x2013;153. https://doi.org/10.1080/15275920490495873</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15275920490495873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh RM, Datta B, Jain A (2004) Identification of unknown groundwater pollution sources using artificial neural networks. J Water Resour Plan Manag 130(6):506&#x2013;514. https://doi.org/10.1061/(asce)0733-9496(2004)130:6(506)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)0733-9496(2004)130:6(506)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava D, Singh RM (2015) Groundwater System Modeling for Simultaneous Identification of Pollution Sources and Parameters with Uncertainty Characterization. Water Resour Manag 29(13):4607&#x2013;4627. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11269-015-1078-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11269-015-1078-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strobl C, Malley J, Tutz G (2009) An Introduction to Recursive Partitioning: Rationale, Application, and Characteristics of Classification and Regression Trees, Bagging, and Random Forests. Psychol Methods 14(4):323&#x2013;348. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0016973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0016973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subha Ramakrishnan M, Ganapathy N (2022) Extreme Gradient Boosting Based Improved Classification of Blood-Brain-Barrier Drugs. Stud Health Technol Inform 294:872&#x2013;873. https://doi.org/10.3233/shti220612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/shti220612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J, Qin C, Li W, Liu C (2019) Intelligent Fault Diagnosis of Diesel Engines via Extreme Gradient Boosting and High-Accuracy Time-Frequency Information of Vibration Signals. Sensors 19(15). https://doi.org/10.3390/s19153280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taormina R, Chau K-W (2015) Data-driven input variable selection for rainfall-runoff modeling using binary-coded particle swarm optimization and Extreme Learning Machines. J Hydrol 529:1617&#x2013;1632. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2015.08.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2015.08.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran VN, Kim J (2022) Robust and efficient uncertainty quantification for extreme events that deviate significantly from the training dataset using polynomial chaos-kriging. J Hydrol 609. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2022.127716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrugt JA, Stauffer PH, Woehling T, Robinson BA, Vesselinov VV (2008) Inverse modeling of subsurface flow and transport properties: A review with new developments. Vadose Zone J 7(2):843&#x2013;864. https://doi.org/10.2136/vzj2007.0078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2136/vzj2007.0078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W-C, Chau K-W, Cheng C-T, Qiu L (2009) A comparison of performance of several artificial intelligence methods for forecasting monthly discharge time series. J Hydrol 374(3-4):294&#x2013;306. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2009.06.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2009.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Lu W, Chang Z, Luo J (2023) A combined search method based on a deep learning combined surrogate model for groundwater DNAPL contamination source identification. J Hydrol 616. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2022.128854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Lu W, Chang Z, Wang H (2022) Simultaneous identification of groundwater contaminant source and simulation model parameters based on an ensemble Kalman filter - Adaptive step length ant colony optimization algorithm. J Hydrol 605. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2021.127352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Zeng X (2013) Review of the uncertainty analysis of groundwater numerical simulation. Chin Sci Bull 58(25):3044&#x2013;3052. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11434-013-5950-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11434-013-5950-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu YR et al (2012) Synergy of satellite and ground based observations in estimation of particulate matter in eastern China. Sci Total Environ 433:20&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2012.06.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2012.06.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Dong W, An Y, Lu W (2019) A Bayesian-based integrated approach for identifying groundwater contamination sources. J Hydrol 579. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2019.124160</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu F, Xu X (2014) A short-term load forecasting model of natural gas based on optimized genetic algorithm and improved BP neural network. Appl Energy 134:102&#x2013;113. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2014.07.104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2014.07.104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J et al (2020) Improving Simulation Efficiency of MCMC for Inverse Modeling of Hydrologic Systems With a Kalman-Inspired Proposal Distribution. Water Resour Res 56(3). https://doi.org/10.1029/2019wr025474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Zhong X, Liu G (2008) Recognizing spatial distribution patterns of grassland insects: neural network approaches. Stoch Env Res Risk A 22(2):207&#x2013;216. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00477-007-0108-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00477-007-0108-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Lu W, Xiao C (2016) A Kriging surrogate model coupled in simulation-optimization approach for identifying release history of groundwater sources. J Contam Hydrol 185:51&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jconhyd.2016.01.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconhyd.2016.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Qu R, Xing Z, Lu W (2020) Identifying groundwater contaminant sources based on a KELM surrogate model together with four heuristic optimization algorithms. Adv Water Resour 138. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.advwatres.2020.103540</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>